<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE preface PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<preface id="foreword">
  <title>Foreword: ${project.version}</title>

  <para>This is an initial pre-alpha version of the Maven Cookbook, and I mean
  "pre-alpha". If you are coming to the book with the expectation that this is
  a polished product, please check back in a few months, we're going to be
  developing this content over the next few months, and you should expect at
  least two chapters a month for the next five or six. I'm convinced that this
  will be a better book because people are going to have a window into the
  process, you will be able to see the false starts, outline revisions, and
  other parts of the writing process that are usually hidden from view. You'll
  be able to give us feedback and reviews even before we've stated that the
  content is ready for review. </para>

  <para>What's up with this cover image (on the PDF)? It is a Galaxy, the
  <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NGC_1300">Barred Spiral Galaxy NGC
  1300</ulink> to be exact, and the picture is a composite of images from
  NASA's Hubble Space Telescope. NGC 1300 is 61 million light-years away and
  it is 110,000 light-years across. Why a Galaxy? Two reasons: First reason,
  because a Galaxy is a good analogy for the ecosystem that surrounds Maven.
  If Maven were the massive energetic core of a galaxy, the various projects
  and plugins that provide Maven's functionality are the various solar systems
  and star clusters that comprise the bulk of what you see when you look at a
  galaxy. While Maven: The Definitive Guide is going to be focused on the core
  of Maven, this book is focused on the various objects one would encounter in
  the "spiral arms". Second reason I used this picture, because it's a cool
  picture that is in the public domain. (Just in case you are curious, your
  own galaxy, The Milky Way, is a Spiral Galaxy that has a logarithmic spiral
  shape, measurements from the Spitzer Space Telescope in 2005 confirmed that
  our own galaxy is a barred spiral galaxy.)</para>

  <para>And another thing, we're calling this thing a "book", but doesn't the
  term seem a bit archaic at the moment? This book is more of a periodical (as
  are most of our books), they change and evolve as the community and software
  evolves. Admittedly, parts of our other books tend to converge to a stable
  point, but even the most basic parts of Maven: The Definitive Guide are open
  to change. Despite this constant evolution, we are currently investigating
  new ways to make this content available as a regular, printed book for those
  of you who would like a copy.</para>

  <para>Tim O'Brien, Sonatype</para>

  <para>July 15, 2009</para>

  <para>Edition: ${project.version}</para>

  <section id="foreword-sect-revisions">
    <title>Revision History</title>

    <para>Many readers have been asking us to keep track of specific changes
    to the book content, the following sections list changes made to the book
    in reverse chronological order starting with ${project.version}.</para>

    <section id="foreword-sect-rev-0_1">
      <title>Changes in Edition 0.1</title>

      <para>The following changes were introduced in Edition 0.1:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Seeded the initial version of the book with the source of the
          Nexus book.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Create a cover for the Maven Cookbook.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Write a Chapter on OSGi Development</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
  </section>
</preface>
